Samantha: An American Girl Holiday is a drama, family,
tv movie film directed by Nadia Tass.
Kindhearted Samantha Parkington's world starts to change
the day Nellie O'Malley walks into her life.
Nellie, her father, and her two little sisters have moved in
next door to be servants for the Ryland family.
Though they come from completely different backgrounds,
Samantha and Nellie become fast friends.
The girls turn to each other in happiness and sorrow, adventure and danger.
Samantha, played by AnnaSophia Robb.
Grandmary Edwards, played by Mia Farrow.
Jenny O'Malley, played by Olivia Ballantyne.
Nellie O'Malley, played by Kelsey Lewis.
Uncle Gard, played by Jordan Bridges.
Aunt Cornelia, played by Rebecca Mader.
Samantha: An American Girl Holiday is a 2004 television film, based on
the American Girl children's books written by Susan S.
Adler and Valerie Tripp.
The film premiered on The WB on November 23, 2004.
The film follows young, wealthy Samantha Parkington's
adventures with three poor orphan girls.
Shot in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, the 86-minute film features lavish period costumes and
settings, and was nominated for three Young Artist Awards, winning one.
Samantha is the first film in the American Girl franchise.
The tone is emotional.